Guide to the Roger W. Moss Collection of Manuscript, Original Art and Printed Material by and about Richard Shirley Smith
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Engravings by Richard Shirley Smith, Series IV
  - Engravings for The Darkening Green, Artist's Proofs, 1964; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 17 x 8.2 cm (Box 12, Item Bain no. 58-67)
    Bain no. 58-67. No inscription.
    Wood engravings; Clarke, Elizabeth. Darkening green
  - Thomas More Artist's Proof, 1964; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7 x 12 cm (Item Bain no. 70)
    Bain no. 70. Inscribed in graphite: "AP St. Thomas More. Richard Shirley Smith 1964."
    A second impression, similarly inscribed, is filed in Box 4, add. 1.
    Reynolds, Ernest Edwin, 1894-. Trial of St. Thomas More; Wood engravings; More, Thomas, Saint, 1478-1535
  - Portrait of R. Vaughan Williams, 1964; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.5 x 3 cm (Item Bain no. 72)
    Bain no. 72. Inscribed in graphite: "Portrait of R.V.W. Richard Shirley Smith '64."
    Wood engravings; Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958
  - Crab Apples and Jug, 1964; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.75 x 7 cm (Item Bain no. 73)
    Bain no. 73. Inscribed in graphite: "AP Richard Shirley Smith."
    Crabapples; Wood engravings
  - Kitchen Table Artist's Proof, 1964; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7 x 12.5 cm (Item Bain no. 75)
    Bain no. 75 ("Illustration for article by Douglas Bartrum in Wine and Food Magazine, 1964.") Inscribed in graphite: "Artist's Proof. 1964. Richard Shirley Smith."
    Wood engravings; Bartrúm, Douglas
  - Table Top, 1964; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 15.75 x 10.5 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 76)
    Bain no. 76. No inscription.
  - Headpiece for Folio Society Artist's Proof, 1965; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.75 x 9.5 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 79)
    Bain no. 79. Inscribed in graphite: "AP Richard Shirley Smith. 1965."
    Wood engravings; Folio Society (London, England)
  - Portrait of Teilhard de Chardin, 1965; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 8 x 12.75 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 81)
    Bain no. 81. Inscribed in graphite: "9/60 Teilhard de Chardin. Richard Shirley Smith 1965."
    A second impression (Box 3, add. 2) is inscribed in graphite "11/60 Teilhard de Chardin. Richard Shirley Smith 1965."
    Wood engravings; Teilhard de Chardin, Pierre
  - Portrait of Erasmus, 1965; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7 x 8 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 82)
    Bain no. 82. Inscribed in graphite: "24/30 Errasmus. Richard Shirley Smith."
    Wood engravings; Erasmus, Desiderius, d. 1536
  - Christmas Card with Scales [Rocket Press imprint], 1965; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 17 x 11 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 83)
    Bain no. 83. No inscription.
    Wood engravings; Christmas cards
  - Engravings for Memoirs of a London Doll, Artist's Proofs, 1967; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.6 x 9 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 117-118)
    Bain no. 117-118. Inscribed in graphite: "A.P. Richard Shirley Smith. 1967."
    Horne, R. H. (Richard H.), 1802-1884. Memoirs of a London doll; Wood engravings
  - Engravings for Memoirs of a London Doll, Artist's Proofs, 1967; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.2 x 6.5 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 120)
    Bain no. 120. Inscribed in graphite: "A.P. Richard Shirley Smith '67."
  - Engravings for Memoirs of a London Doll, Artist's Proofs, 1967; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.6 x 4.6 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 121)
    Bain no. 121. Inscribed in graphite: "AP Richard Shirley Smith '67."
  - Engravings for Memoirs of a London Doll, Artist's Proofs, 1967; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7.6 x 4.7 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 122)
    Bain no. 122. Inscribed in graphite: "A.P. Richard Shirley Smith '67."
  - Engravings for Memoirs of a London Doll, Artist's Proofs, 1967; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.6 x 9 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 124)
    Bain no. 124. Inscribed in graphite: "A.P. Richard Shirley Smith. '67."
  - Engravings for Memoirs of a London Doll, Artist's Proofs, 1967; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.1 x 9.1 cm (Box 13, Item Bain no. 130-131)
    Bain no. 130-131. Inscribed in graphite: "A.P. Richard Shirley Smith '67."
  - The Old Rectory for Auberon Waugh, 1967; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6.25 x 10.5 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 132a)
    Bain no. 132a. Inscribed in graphite: "Richard Shirley Smith."
    Chilton Foliat (Wiltshire, England); Wood engravings; Waugh, Auberon
  - The Old Rectory for Auberon Waugh, 1967; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6.25 x 10.5 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 132b)
    Bain no. 132b. No inscription.
    Wood engravings; Chilton Foliat (Wiltshire, England); Waugh, Auberon
  - Upper Upham for John Anstey, 1968–1980; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6.5 x 9.5 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 134)
    Bain no. 134. Inscribed in graphite: "14/60 1968. Richard Shirley Smith."
    Upper Upham (Wiltshire, England); Wood engravings
  - Cupid's Progress Artist's Proofs, 1970; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9.5 x 12 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 161)
    Bain no. 161. No inscription.
    Wood engravings; Cupid, (Roman deity)
  - Cupid's Progress Artist's Proofs, 1970; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9.5 x 12 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 162)
    Bain no. 162. No inscription.
  - Cupid's Progress Artist's Proofs, 1970; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9.5 x 12 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 163)
    Bain no. 163. No inscription.
  - Cupid's Progress Artist's Proofs, 1970; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9.5 x 12 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 164)
    Bain no. 164. No inscription.
  - Shelley at Baths of Caracalla, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7.25 x 10 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 165)
    Bain no. 165. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Shelley. 1. Richard Shirley Smith '71."
    Wood engravings; Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Baths of Caracalla (Rome, Italy)
  - Shelley's boat, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7 x 3.25 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 166)
    Bain no. 166. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 2."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Keats's death mask with flowers in Rome, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 7 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 167)
    Bain no. 167. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 3."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Keats, John, 1795-1821
  - Portrait of Jane Williams, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4 x 5.5 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 168)
    Bain no. 168. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 4."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Williams, Jane, 1798-1884
  - Jane with guitar in pinewood, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 6 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 169)
    Bain no. 169. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 5."
  - Santa Maria Della Salute, Venice, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 11.5 x 5.5 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 170)
    Bain no. 170. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 6."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Chiesa di S. Maria della salute (Venice, Italy)
  - Mont Blanc with broken pine trees, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.75 x 7.75 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 171)
    Bain no. 171. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 7."
    Blanc, Mont (France and Italy); Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Monuments in desert, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7.5 x 6.25 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 172)
    Bain no. 172. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 8."
  - Pyramid near Protestant Cemetery, Rome, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4 x 9 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 173)
    Bain no. 173. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 9."
    Rome (Italy); Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Butterflies on flower, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7.5 x 6 cm (Box 14, Item Bain no. 174)
    Bain no. 174. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 10."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Butterflies
  - Grasshopper, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.5 x 5 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 175)
    Bain no. 175. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 11."
    Grasshoppers; Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Matted tree root, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 2.5 x 7.5 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 176)
    Bain no. 176. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 12."
    Roots (Botany); Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Spider, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 2.5 x 3 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 177)
    Bain no. 177. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 13."
    Spiders; Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Toad, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.5 x 2.75 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 178)
    Bain no. 178. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 14."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Toads; Wood engravings
  - Owl, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3 x 3.5 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 179)
    Bain no. 179. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 15."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Owls
  - Flowery wreath, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6 x 9 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 180)
    Bain no. 180. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 16."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wreaths; Wood engravings
  - Flowers and skull in basket, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.5 x 8 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 181)
    Bain no. 181. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 17."
    Flowers; Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Wreathed urn, cone spear & curtain, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.5 x 7.75 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 182)
    Bain no. 182. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 18."
  - Head of pan, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5 x 4 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 183)
    Bain no. 183. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 19."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Pan, (Greek deity)
  - Vignette, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 2.5 x 4.5 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 184)
    Bain no. 184. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 20."
  - William Shelley as a small boy with toy, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.5 x 5 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 185)
    Bain no. 185. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 21."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Shelley, William, 1816-1819
  - Contessina Emilia Viviani, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5 x 3.25 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 186)
    Bain no. 186. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 22."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Viviani, Teresa, 1801-1836
  - Two vast and trunkless legs of stone, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 6.5 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 187)
    Bain no. 187. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 23."
  - Crown & mitre with fluttering monsters, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 6.5 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 188)
    Bain no. 188. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 24."
  - Draped pensive woman in Roman ruins, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 5.75 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 189)
    Bain no. 189. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 25."
  - Dark tower in water against sunset, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 6.5 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 190)
    Bain no. 190. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 26."
  - Aphrodite in Greek temple, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 6 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 191)
    Bain no. 191. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 27."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings; Aphrodite, (Greek deity)
  - Moths and moon, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 6 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 192)
    Bain no. 192. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 28."
    Moths; Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Volcano and islanded lake, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6.75 x 8.25 cm (Box 15, Item Bain no. 193)
    Bain no. 193. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 29."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Volcanoes; Wood engravings
  - Veiled maid in jungle, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.5 x 7.75 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 194)
    Bain no. 194. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 30."
  - Moon behind cloud, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6 x 4.75 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 195)
    Bain no. 195. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 31."
    Moon; Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Endymion in moonlight, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.75 x 7.75 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 196)
    Bain no. 196. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 32."
    Endymion (Greek mythology); Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Anarchy - skeleton rider, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7.75 x 5.5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 197)
    Bain no. 197. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 33."
  - Reclining girl's head with flowers, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.5 x 6.25 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 198)
    Bain no. 198. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 34."
  - Girl offering chalice, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3 x 7.5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 199)
    Bain no. 199. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith. 1971. Shelley 35."
  - Dead girl in the rain, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.5 x 5.5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 200)
    Bain no. 200. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 36."
    Death; Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wood engravings
  - Lattice window open in moonlight, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.25 x 5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 201)
    Bain no. 201. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 Richard Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 37."
  - The Devil's chase, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.25 x 5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 202)
    Bain no. 201. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 R. Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 38."
  - Death of Liberty, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.25 x 5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 203)
    Bain no. 201. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 R. Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 39."
  - Death at death bed, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.25 x 5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 204)
    Bain no. 204. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 R. Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 40."
  - Yawning head, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.25 x 5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 205)
    Bain no. 205. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 R. Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 41."
  - Smiling face, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 3.25 x 5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 206)
    Bain no. 206. Inscribed in graphite: "7/25 R. Shirley Smith '71. Shelley 42."
  - Woman and Hackney Cab Shelley, for Poems of Shelley, Artist's Proof, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.25 x 6.5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 210)
    Bain no. 210. Inscribed in graphite: "AP Richard Shirley Smith."
  - Engravings for Letters to His Son, 1973; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.75 x 9.5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 217)
    Bain no. 217. Inscribed in graphite: "5/60 Richard Shirley Smith. '74."
    Wood engravings; Chesterfield, Philip Dormer Stanhope, Earl of, 1694-1773. Letters to his son
  - Engravings for Letters to His Son, 1973; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.5 x 9.75 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 218)
    Bain no. 218. Inscribed in graphite: "5/60 Richard Shirley Smith '74."
    Chesterfield, Philip Dormer Stanhope, Earl of, 1694-1773. Letters to his son; Wood engravings
  - Combe Florey House for Auberon Waugh, 1973; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6.25 x 10.25 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 229)
    Bain no. 229. Inscribed in graphite: "AP. Richard Shirley Smith 1973."
    Wood engravings; Combe Florey House (Combe Florey, Somerset, England); Waugh, Auberon
  - Cove House for Giles FitzHerbert, 1973; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.25 x 7.5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 230)
    Bain no. 230. Inscribed in graphite: "AP. Richard Shirley Smith 1973."
    Wood engravings; FitzHerbert, Giles Eden, 1935-2011; Cove House (Devon, England)
  - Libanus Press Logo, 1975; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 2.5 x 2.5 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 235)
    Bain no. 235. No inscription.
    Wood engravings; Libanus Press
  - Horsenden Manor for Mrs. J. Gourlay, 1976; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6 x 10 cm (Box 16, Item Bain no. 237a)
    Bain no. 237a. Inscribed in graphite: "29/60 Richard Shirley Smith '76."
    Wood engravings; Horsenden Manor (Wycombe, England)
  - Greens Old Farm for Martin Trowell (1976), Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6.5 x 9 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 237b)
    Bain no. 237b. Inscribed in graphite: "AP. Richard Shirley Smith. 1976."
  - Nymph and Pulcinella Artist's Proof, 1976; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5 x 7.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 238)
    Bain no. 238. Inscribed in graphite: "AP Richard Shirley Smith '76."
    Nymphs (Greek deities); Punchinello (Fictitious character); Wood engravings
  - Frontispiece for The Closed Door, 1977; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 9 x 6.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 239)
    Bain no. 239. Inscribed in graphite: "A.P. '77 Richard Shirley Smith."
    Reeves, James. Closed door; Wood engravings
  - Churchyard for Six Hampshire Epitaphs, 1977; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4 x 7.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 240)
    Bain no. 240. Inscribed in graphite: "xlvii/50 Richard Shirley Smith '77."
    Six Hampshire epitaphs; Wood engravings
  - Bookplate for Michael Valentine Briton Riviere, 1978; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 6.5 x 8.25 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 241)
    Bain no. 241. Inscribed in graphite: "18/60 Richard Shirley Smith."
  - Doric detail for invitation card, 1978; Shirley Smith, Richard (Box 17, Item Bain no. 243b)
    Columns, Doric; Wood engravings
  - Portrait of Pépé, 1980; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 8 x 6.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 245)
    Bain no. 245. Inscribed in graphite: "AP Richard Shirley Smith."
    Cats; Wood engravings
  - Winfrith Court for Anthony Jaggard, 1980; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7 x 10.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 250)
    Bain no. 250. Inscribed in graphite: "57/80 Richard Shirley Smith 1980."
    Wood engravings; Jaggard, Anthony; Winfrith Court (Winfrith Newburgh, Dorset, England)
  - Frontispiece 'Rhinoceros Beetle' for Buzz-Buzz, 1978; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 12 x 9.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 251)
    Bain no. 251. Inscribed in graphite: "AP Richard Shirley Smith 1978."
    Heath-Stubbs, John, 1918-2006. Buzz buzz; Rhinoceros beetle; Wood engravings
  - Girl's Head for Vines, 1984; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7.25 x 6.25 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 258)
    Bain no. 258. Inscribed in graphite: "96/100 Richard Shirley Smith '84."
    Wood engravings; Burnett, David, 1937-. Vines
  - Colophon for Collins Harvill, 1964; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.5 x 2.75 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 264)
    Bain no. 264. Inscribed in graphite: "Harvil Colophon. Richard Shirley Smith."
    Wood engravings; Collins Harvill
  - Two Fantastics, 1984; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 12 x 9 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 283)
    Bain no. 283. Inscribed in graphite: "AP. Richard Shirley Smith 1984."
    Wood engravings; Thacker, Christopher. Enchanting paths to paradise
  - Painshill, 1989; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.5 x 9.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 285)
    Bain no. 285. Inscribed in graphite: "xiii/50 Painshill - Richard Shirley Smith 1989."
    Painshill Park (England); Thacker, Christopher. Enchanting paths to paradise; Wood engravings
  - Stourhead, 1989; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.5 x 9.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 286)
    Bain no. 286. Inscribed in graphite: "xiii/50 Stourhead. Richard Shirley Smith. 1989."
    Thacker, Christopher. Enchanting paths to paradise; Wood engravings; Stourhead (England)
  - Fonthill Splendens, 1989; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.5 x 9.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 287)
    Bain no. 287. Inscribed in graphite: "xiii/50 Fonthill Splendens. Richard Shirley Smith '89."
    Thacker, Christopher. Enchanting paths to paradise; Wood engravings; Fonthill Abbey
  - Fonthill Abbey, 1989; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 5.5 x 9.5 cm (Box 17, Item Bain no. 288)
    Bain no. 288. Inscribed in graphite: "xiii/50 Fonthill Abbey. Richard Shirley Smith '89."
  - Gerald Finzi's Music Room, circa 1958; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 10.5 x 8 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [1])
    Not in Bain. Inscribed in graphite: "Gerald Finzi's music room c. 1958."
    Wood engravings; Finzi, Gerald, 1901-1956
  - Nude in Garden, 1960; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4 x 7.7 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [2])